var questions = [
    { 
question : "who is a founder of India ?",
option1:" A : Mahatma Gandhi",
option2:" B : Liqat Ali khan",
option3:" C : APJ abdual kalm",
option4:" D : Shoukat Ali",
answer:"1"
},{
question : "What is a capital of pakistan?",
option1:" A : Karachi",
option2:" B : Islamabad",
option3:" C : Peshawer",
option4:" D : Lahore",
answer:"2"
},{
question : "What is national game of pakistan?",
option1:" A : Football",
option2:" B : Cricket",
option3:" C : Hockey",
option4:" D : Snooker",
answer:"3"
},{
question : "What is a currency name of India?",
option1:" A : Riyal",
option2:" B : Pounds",
option3:" C : US Dollar",
option4:" D : Rupeee",
answer:"4"
},{
question : "Who is Current president of pakistan?",
option1:" A : Arif Alvi",
option2:" B : Rajab Tayyab",
option3:" C : Shehzada Salman",
option4:" D : Pervaiz Musharraf",
answer:"1"
},{
question : "Who is current manager of google?",
option1:" A : Moen Khan",
option2:" B : Pichai Sundararajan",
option3:" C : Bill grts",
option4:" D : Jack Ma",
answer:"2"
},{
question : "What is means of HTML?",
option1:" A : High time mile limit",
option2:" B : Help to more leaf",
option3:" C : Hyper text markup language",
option4:" D : Height to mine lamp",
answer:"3"
},{
question : "What is a means of IBM?",
option1:" A : Internet byte mega",
option2:" B : Inter by mine",
option3:" C : Intenet by mobile",
option4:" D : Internation business machine",
answer:"4"
},{
question : "Where is a pakistan in world?",
option1:" A : Asia",
option2:" B : Eourpe",
option3:" C : Aalantika",
option4:" D : South Africa",
answer:"1"
},{
question : "Where is a main center of Faizan-e-Madina in pakistan?",
option1:" A : Lahore",
option2:" B : Karachi",
option3:" C : Peshawar",
option4:" D : Multan",
answer:"2"
}
]



var currentQuestion = 0;
var score = 0;
var totalQuestion = questions.length;

var container = document.getElementById("quizQuestion");
var questionE = document.getElementById("question");
var opt1 = document.getElementById("opt1");
var opt2 = document.getElementById("opt2");
var opt3 = document.getElementById("opt3");
var opt4 = document.getElementById("opt4");
var nextBtn = document.getElementById("nextButton");
var result = document.getElementById("result");


function LoadQuestion(questionIndex){
var q = questions[questionIndex];
question.textContent = (questionIndex +1)+". "+q.question;
opt1.textContent = q.option1;
opt2.textContent = q.option2;
opt3.textContent = q.option3;
opt4.textContent = q.option4;

}

function LoadNextQuestion(){
var selectOption = document.querySelector("input[type=radio]:checked");
if(!selectOption){
alert("please select your answer!")
return;
}

var answer1 = selectOption.value;
if(questions[currentQuestion].answer == answer1){
score += 1000;
}
selectOption.checked = false;
currentQuestion++;
if(currentQuestion == totalQuestion -1){
nextBtn.textContent = "Finish";
}
if(currentQuestion == totalQuestion){
container.style.display = "none";
result.style.display = "";
result.textContent = "Congratulation You have Won: $"+ score;
return;
}
LoadQuestion(currentQuestion);
}

LoadQuestion(currentQuestion);

